Pablo Obando Senior Full Stack Engineer



I'm a passionate full-stack software developer with 6+ years of experience developing web pages and apps, focused on improving user experiences and ensuring top-notch UI code quality in all project-related processes.

I help companies develop software products and make technical decisions, taking ideas from conception to production, and successful execution.

Work Experience

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2023

Senior Full Stack Developer @ Parsley Health

At Parsley Health, a pioneer in holistic healthcare empowering individuals to overcome chronic conditions, I collaborated in impactful projects ensuring timely and budget-compliant deliveries.

- Participate in the website migration from WordPress to gatsby/react.
- Participate in a full redesign of our marketing website, delivering on time with limited resources.
- Optimized conversion rates for the primary checkout flow and integrate TDD
- Established A/B testing tools and mechanisms to drive optimization and insights.
- Led the maintenance and enhancement of our primary checkout flow.
- Work with agile methodologies, employ test-iterate-repeat cycles, and launch Minimum Viable Products (MVPs) when possible.

typescript tailwind graphql react.js next.js aws docker

JULY 2020 - JUNE 2021

Full Stack Developer @ Quext

At Quext, a game-changing property management platform, I led tech-driven improvements, enhancing user experience and functionality.

- UI Enhancement: Lead the creation and maintenance of user-friendly web apps.
- Multilingual Support: Implemented i18n for a global user base.
- Work with multiple cross-functional teams to achieve organizational goals.

typescript tailwind node.js react.js vue.js nest.js aws

Front End Developer @ Blockmatic

At Blockmatic, a Web3 Product Studio, I worked in a frontend team creating new designs from figma on next.js using Tailwind, I participate in the development of the projects:

- Migrate social media from Wordpress to next.js, enhancing the performance and boosting user engagement.
- Redesigned a cryptocurrency exchange platform with next.js, creating a more user-friendly and efficient interface, positively impacting the user experience.

typescript tailwind node.js next.js graphql heroku hasura

JUNE 2018 - JUNE 2019

Back end Stack Developer @ BananaCode

At Bananacode, a digital firm based on San Jose CR, where we loved to build solutions based on the users needs.

- Participate in the creation of a robust backend for a digital journalism platform ensuring seamless content delivery.
- CMS Development: Built a journalist-focused Content Management System (CMS), streamlining content management and publication.
- Subscription Model: Designed and implemented a flexible subscription system, enhancing user engagement and monetization with tier-based content access on the journalist.
- Component Crafting: Developed custom react.js components using styled components, UI/UX.

typescript react.js react native angular graphql express

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

Front End Developer @ Nw Ideas

At Nw Ideas, a digital agency based on San Jose CR, my initial role involved collaborating with a seasoned professional team to deliver cutting-edge digital experiences.

 Development bank's affiliation score app that enables clients to earn and redeem points with affiliated merchants, streamlining content management and enhancing user engagement.

javascript react.js react native php css3

Education

MAY 2017 - DECEMBER 2021

Computer Science @ Fidélitas University

javascript python html5 oop solid mob programming

Stack

Frameworks & Libraries

mongodb	express	react.js	node.js	tailwind	cypress
storybook	cypress	node.js	gatsby	react native	google cloud
apollo	graphQl	prisma	jest	firebase	styled components

Software & Applications

postgresql	discord	docker	mysql	figma	slack	mongodb
confluence	jira	aws				

Third Party Services

netlify github gitlab vercel

Links

https://obandev.io

https://github.com/obandev
https://twitter.com/obandev_io
https://linkedin.com/in/obandev